If they've really got what it takes, it's going to take everything they've got.
Fame is a drama, music film directed by Alan Parker.
A chronicle of the lives of several teenagers who attend a New York
high school for students gifted in the performing arts.
Coco, played by Irene Cara.
Ralph, played by Barry Miller.
Doris Finsecker, played by Maureen Teefy.
Montgomery, played by Paul McCrane.
Bruno, played by Lee Curreri.
Leroy, played by Gene Anthony Ray.
Fame is a 1980 American teen musical drama film directed by
Alan Parker and written by Christopher Gore.
Set in New York City, it chronicles the lives and hardships of students attending The High School of
Performing Arts, from their auditions to their freshman, sophomore, junior, and senior years.
Producer David De Silva conceived the premise in 1976,
partially inspired by the musical A Chorus Line.
He commissioned playwright Gore to write the script, originally titled
Hot Lunch, before selling it to Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (MGM).
After he was hired to direct the film, Parker rewrote the script
with Gore, aiming for a darker and more dramatic tone.
The script's subject matter received criticism by the New York Board of Education, which
prevented the production from filming in the actual High School of Performing Arts.
The film was shot on location in New York City, with principal
photography beginning in July 1979 and concluding after 91 days.
Parker encountered a difficult filming process,
which included conflicts with U.S.
labor unions over various aspects of the film's production.
Fame received a limited release beginning at the Ziegfeld Theatre in New York City on May 12,
1980, and had a wide release in the United States on June 20, by United Artists.
The film grossed more than $42 million worldwide
against a production budget of $8.5 million.
It initially received a mixed response from reviewers who praised the music, but criticized the
dramatic tone, pacing and direction although the film has been reappraised over the years.
The film received several awards and nominations, including two Academy Awards for Best Original Song
("Fame") and Best Original Score, and a Golden Globe Award for Best Original Song ("Fame").
Its success spawned a media franchise encompassing several television
series, a stage musical, and a remake released in 2009.
In 2023, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of new york city, dance,
dance performance, musical, rivalry.
The tone is emotional.